QIANG HAN

Software Development Engineer

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Development Engineer with a Master's degree in Communication Information Engineering. Specializes in camera imaging, multimedia, and cloud networking software development. Successfully led project development, practiced Agile methodologies as a Scrum Master, and drove innovation in complex technical environments.

+86 13811001112

qianq.han@hotmail.com

in/qiang-han

github.com/qiang-han

SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, Bash, Python

Technologies: Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Camera &

Imaging, Media Transportation, Network-

ing

PROJECTS

Technical Leader

Media Communications Mesh

https://github.com/OpenVisualCloud/Media-Communications-Mesh

Led the development of an efficient, low-latency, and high-throughput media transport service mesh framework, optimizing for microservices architectures. Collaborated with architects to fine-tune design and led project development and management, ensuring milestones were met. Implemented key features such as zero-copy transportation, SMPTE 2110 standards, NMOS integration, and Kubernetes orchestration.

Technical Leader

E2E Media Pipeline

Led the development of the "E2E Media Pipeline" program, delivering a benchmarking tool to develop a reference media pipeline for Intel platforms. Developed key features using the FFmpeg "libav" library, including performance and quality benchmarking, parallel running model, and high configurability. Instrumental in analyzing media performance on existing and next-gen "Xeon" platforms.

Technical Leader

Camera Automated Test Suit

Designed and developed a comprehensive automated test framework for Intel's high-end camera and imaging systems. Fully automated the complete workflow of camera validation tasks, encompassing case management, test execution, automatic result analysis, bug auto-submission, and test report generation.

Technical Leader

IPU System Test Automation

Designed and implemented an automated testing framework for Intel's Image Processing Unit (IPU) system, achieving and maintaining automation rate over 90% across 2,000+ test cases. Developed innovative automated solutions for critical IPU tests, such as ATE bit-match, static analysis (Klocwork/Protex/BDBA), and compliance testing, substantially increasing test efficiency and reliability.

Project Management

Validation Project Leader

Served as the Validation Project Leader for various Intel IPU projects, managing the full validation process from requirements analysis to test case development. Expertly coordinated project schedules and resource allocation, formulated comprehensive test plans, and ensured the timely progression of both development and validation phases. Employed 'Agile' methodologies as a Scrum Master, host regular scrum meetings and was a key contributor to the scrum team.

EDUCATION

9/2004 - 3/2007 **Master of Science in Engineering** **Beihang University**

Specialty: Communication Information Engineering

9/1996 - 7/2000

Bachelor of Engineering

Tianjin Polytechnic University

Specialty: Computer Science and Application

EXPERIENCE

11/2021 - Present System Software Development Engineer, NEX (Network & Edge Group)

Intel Corporation

· Develop software about multi-media, video codec, and cloud networking. Optimize software design and implementation to achieve the maximum performance on Xeon platforms.

C / C++ / Service Mesh / Kubernetes / SMPTE 2110 / NMOS / FFmpeg

2/2011 - 11/2021 Senior Software Engineer, ICG (Imaging and Camera Technologies Group)

Intel Corporation

· Engaged in software development and validation for "Camera & Imaging" system, including design and develop test framework and test tools, test automation, validation project management etc.

C / Python / Gtk+ / OpenCV / Android / Agile

	Software Engineer SMS client, OSD components on "Skylight" mobile Linux / C / Gtk+ / OpenEmbedded	Lenovo Corporate Research & Development e device.
•	Software Engineer Network computer (NC) Terminals and the Servers Digital photo frame application Linux / C / Gtk+	Beijing Peking University Unity Microsystems Technology Co., Ltd. s management system
Internship .	Software Engineer Data Link Gateway Server System for CAAC The Surveillance System of the Flight for the Airline Linux / C / Gtk+ / SNMP / Oracle9i	
	Software Engineer ERP system for company daily business managem ASP / JavaScript / VBScript / IBM DB2	_

INNOVATION -

- E2E Media Pipeline for Platform Performance Evaluation & Optimization SWPC, 2022
- Automated SWQRC Report in ICG Dashboard System SWPC, 2019
- Hybrid Camera Simulation Solution for Pre-Silicon Development DTTC, 2017
- Intellectual Test Case Selection Strategy SWPC, 2017
- Smart Light Booth Based on Intel Edison I2R, 2016
- Deploy Test Management System using Intel Internal Cloud Service SWPC, 2016
- Network Management System Based on AgentX Extensible Network Management Model Application Research of Computers, 2006

LANGUAGES -

English - proficient, Chinese - native